# PEDRO ENDARA

# FRONTEND DEVELOPER



Phone: 593 98 331 9966 Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/pjendara email: pjendara@gmail.com

Full Stack Developer with great passion for frontend development. With training and background in communication and graphic design. Experienced in projects working with React, Redux, HTML, CSS, JS, NodeJS, SQL among others technologies. With creative thinking, great curiosity that drives me to find and understand how things work. Communication, adaptability, and good eye to recognize relevant information and find out the cause or possible cause for troubles.

I combine the best of both worlds: The freedom of a creative and artistic mind... with the discipline and structure of logical and reasoned thinking.

## Education

- 😭 Full Stack Web Developer. Henry Bootcamp. 700 hours. 2020.
- Design and Visual Communication. PUCE 2008 - 2012.
- Bachelor of Science in Communication. CCC-NWC. 2003 - 2007

### Interests

- Music
- Sports
- ♥ Podcast & Radio

## Languages

- Español (Native)
- English (B2)

#### More at:

https://pjota-lab.vercel.app/

## **Technologies**

HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Redux, Node.js, Express, Postgres, Sequelize, Git, Github, Trello, Bootstrap, Illustrator, Photoshop, Premiere, Audition, MongoDB, Typescript, Figma, Scrum.

## **Projects**

## Coin+

Role: Fullstack Developer

Final proyect developed as part of the SoyHenry's bootcamp along with other six people. It is a Web App that offers cryptocurrency exchange services on the Ethereum network. You can buy cripto, exchange it for another crypto or sell it back again. For the Frontend it was used React, Redux toolkit, AuthO, Axios, Bootstrap, Cloudinary, Sweet alert, Swiper, Nodemailer, Mailtrap and Paypal. The Backend was developed with Node.js, Express, Typescript, Typegoose, Mongoose. For the Data Base MongoDB and Mongo Atlas. For the connection and operation of the cryptocurrencies it was used Solidity, Hardhat, Alchemy and Metamask.

## Countrie's App

Role: Fullstack Developer

Web App for consulting information on countries and tourist activities. React, Redux, and CSS were used for the Frontend. The Backend was developed in Node.js with Express. The Data base in PostgreSQL and Sequelize.

## Experience

Freelance / Graphic Design Services Designer - Video Producer 2017 - 2022

- Social Media Management
- Graphic and Advertising Material Production
- Seminars and Online Events Production

## Practicamente Multimedia Designer

2015 - 2017

- Graphic arts production
- Preparation of blueprints
- Supervise production and shipment of products